<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phil Ross, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Phil Ross, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a protein biochemist by training, but a biologist with broad interests that range from the atomic to organismal scale in principle. I have a B.S. in Bioengineering from Binghamton University and a Ph.D. in Genetics from the University of Chicago.
As a computational biologist in the lab of Manuel Llinás, I contributed to studies of transcriptional regulation in Plasmodium falciparum, which inspired me pursue a Ph.D. in order to learn more about life at the molecular scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reads</title>
      <link>/blog/reads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/reads/</guid>
      <description>These are readings I would like to remember and come back to from time to time and will be updated on occasion.
The bus ticket theory of genius
A trilogy on human genetics
Our vast, shared family tree Your ancestors lived all over the world Where did your genetic ancestors come from? Beware adaptationist story-telling: The spandrels of San Marco
The viruses that made us human</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Cytokine engineering in the Mendoza Lab
Coming soon!
Molecular immunology in the Adams Lab
Coming sooner!
Plasmodium computational genomics in the Llinás Lab
As a member of the Llinás Lab I contributed to work in understanding transcriptional regulation in the deadliest human infecting parasite that causes malaria, Plasmodium falciparum.
Primary contributions resulted in the following publications:
Red Blood Cell Invasion by the Malaria Parasite Is Coordinated by the PfAP2-I Transcription Factor Refining the transcriptome of the human malaria parasite Plasmodium falciparum using amplification-free RNA-seq Want to invstigate our data yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
